SUZANNE THORNTON, PHD

Philadelphia, PA | 863-370-9389 | thornton.suzy@gmail.com | dr-suz.github.io

SUMMARY

A statistician with over four years of college-level teaching experience who is eager to transition into a profession of practice. Proven leadership skills both within and outside of academia. Strong statistical theorist with good programming background and excellent communication abilities.

WORK EXPERIENCE

National Institute of Standards and Technology PREP Postdoctoral Assistant George Washington University

Jan 2024 - Present Washington D.C.

Assistant professor of statistics

Sept 2020 - Dec 2023

Swarthmore College

Swarthmore, PA

- Published two original technical papers for a statistics journal and a philosophy of science journal.
- Published three chapters for two forthcoming books on ethical statistical practice and on methods that unify Bayesian, fiducial, and frequentist inference.
- Published several non-technical statistical papers in regarding data equity and ethical statistics/data science practice.
- Designed and taught three undergraduate statistics courses that incorporate ethical reasoning.

Special government employee

Aug 2022 - Dec 2023

US Census Bureau National Advisory Committee on Racial, Ethnic, and Other Populations

Washington, D.C.

- Ascertain the needs and best practices to improve censuses, surveys, operations, and programs.
- Advocate for careful consideration of the collection and analysis of categorical data and for ethical data collection and analysis practices.

Visiting assistant professor of statistics

Oct 2019 - Aug 2020

Swarthmore College

Swarthmore, PA

 Published several non-technical statistical papers in Significance Magazine and AMSTAT News regarding inclusion of LGBT+ populations in statistics and data science.

Statistical consultant

Sept 2016 – Aug 2019

Office of Statistical Consulting, Rutgers University

New Brunswick, NJ

- Published "Development and validation of a predictive model of drug-resistant genetic generalized epilepsy" in *Neurology* as a result of work with a client at Robert Wood Johnson Hospital.
- Published "Exact inference on the random-effects model for meta-analyses with few studies" in *Biometrics* while working with several consulting clients.

EDUCATION

Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey

Oct 2019

Doctor of Philosophy in Statistics and Biostatistics

New Brunswick, NJ

Thesis: Advanced computing methods for statistical inference

University of Florida

May 2014

Bachelor of Science in Mathematics and in Statistics

Gainesville, FL

Thesis: Geometric ergodicity of Gibbs sampler for a hierarchical random effects model: Re-explained

PROGRAMMING	ì
-------------	---

- R ¹	- RMarkdown ¹		
Tools and Software			
 Command Line/Linux² 	- SQL ²	- Python ²	
OTHER			

¹Expert

²Proficient

- Statistical modeling¹
 Data visualization¹

- Academic writing¹
 Non-technical writing¹
- LateX¹
 Git²